this is where we finished at the end of
这就是我们结束的地方
the last part um and we are ready for
最后一部分嗯 我们已经准备好了
some materials before we continue do a
在我们继续之前 先做一些材料
check over though because I looked
不过 请检查一下 因为我看了
inside my dut and I saw
在我的DUT里 我看到
this which shouldn't be here obviously
这显然不应该出现在这里
so make sure you don't have any hidden
所以要确保你没有任何隐藏的
meshes that should definitely not be
绝对不应该使用的网格
there you've only got your camera your
在那里 你只带了你的相机
donate your icing and your light okay
捐献你的糖衣和光芒好吗
okay so materials let's do some
好的 材料 让我们做一些
materials if we jumped into our render
材质 如果我们跳到我们的渲染
mode that little uh button that I showed
打开我展示的那个小按钮
you on the first part that takes you
你在第一部分 你需要你
into rended View mode you can see we've
进入租借视图模式 您可以看到我们
got a lamp and it's lighting our dut in
有一盏灯 它照亮了我们的垃圾堆
a very depressing cold gray so let's
非常令人沮丧的冷灰色 所以让我们
give it a material down here the little
给它一个材料在这里的小
material Tab and then we're going to hit
材料选项卡 然后我们将点击
new so just like before the one thing
新的 就像以前一样
we're going to change is the color let's
我们要换的是颜色 让我们
make it a nice pink color
把它变成漂亮的粉色
and that looks pretty good the other
另外一个看起来很不错
value that you typically want to change
您通常希望更改的值
um for a lot of objects is the roughness
嗯 对于很多物体来说 是粗糙度
value so you can see the further I go
价值 这样你就能看到我走得越远
all the way to the left hand side the
一直到左手边
more it becomes a mirror so all the way
更多的是它变成了一面镜子 所以一路走来
at zero is basically a mirror um and
零基本上是一面镜子
then all the way to the right is your
然后一直往右走就是你的
like most porous object uh like a brick
像大多数多孔物体 呃 像砖头一样
or something like that basically
或者类似的东西 基本上
something that looks like it doesn't
一些看起来不像的东西
have a reflection although everything
有一个反省 尽管一切
does um the roughness is uh is just
这个粗糙度是不是呃就是
merely ipating that reflection um
只是模仿那个倒影 嗯
everywhere so it appears as though it
到处都是 所以它看起来好像
doesn't but anyways so we're going to go
没有 但不管怎样 我们要走了
with like a point uh yeah 3 something
有一分 嗯 对 3分左右
like that that's pretty good and then
就像那样 这很好 然后
for the base of our donut we're going to
对于我们的甜甜圈底座 我们将
give it uh another material and let's go
给它 呃 另一个材料 然后我们走
with a nice orangey yellow which we will
带着漂亮的橙黄色 我们会
change later on so it won't matter
以后再改 这样就不会有什么关系了
anyway um but that's good great look at
不管怎样 嗯 但那是很好的 很棒的
us we've got a donut by the way we'll
我们 顺便说一句 我们有一个甜甜圈
add some
加一些
subsurface SSS later on uh to make this
地下SSS稍后呃来制作这个
look a little bit more milky but for now
看起来有点乳白色 但就目前而言
this is good now we want to put put our
这很好 现在我们想把我们的
donut onto a marble countertop so first
先把甜甜圈放在大理石台面上
of all we need that countertop as a
最重要的是 我们需要台面作为
separate object so shift a and the one
分开的对象 所以移动a和1
we're looking for is again under mesh
我们正在寻找的伊斯兰国又一次被网住了
and we're going to go with a plane so a
我们将乘坐一架飞机 所以
plane is just a square um that's
飞机只是一个正方形 这是
literally made up of four vertices it's
从字面上看是由四个顶点组成的
the simplest object but the most
最简单的物体 但也是最
versatile that you use it all over the
多才多艺 你可以把它用在
place and I'm going to make this look a
我要让它看起来像是
little bit bigger so let's just scale
再大一点 让我们来扩展一下
that out with s and then click okay so
和S一起出去 然后点击OK 所以
we want to make our donut rest on to the
我们想把我们的甜甜圈放在
countertop so if I selected my donut
所以如果我选择了我的甜甜圈
base and moved it up well there's a
然后把它往上移 好的 有一个
problem right we need to have both of
问题是 我们需要两个都有
these move together so if you want to
它们一起移动 所以如果你想
have one object basically attached to
基本上有一个对象附着到
another object while still being its own
另一个物体 同时仍然是它自己的
separate object um you parent it so the
分离对象 嗯 将其设置为父对象 因此
way we parent it is first of all you
我们孕育它的方式首先是你
select the object that you want to
选择想要的对象
follow the other object so the child um
跟随另一个物体 所以孩子嗯
and then you select the parent so
然后选择父级 这样
holding down shift I'm going to now
按住Shift 我现在就去
click on the donut base and then to
点击甜甜圈底座 然后点击
parent its control p key okay or again
将其Ctrl p键设置为父对象 确定或再次
if at any time you don't know what it is
如果在任何时候你不知道这是什么
just hit F3 for search and then we can
只需按F3进行搜索 然后我们就可以
just type in parent now by the way with
顺便说一句 现在只需输入Parent
uh with parent you get a number of
呃 有了父母 你会得到很多
options here uh the one you actually
这里的选项 呃 你实际选择的那个
want is keep transform if you just do
想要的是保持变换 如果你只是这样做
object it means if you've ever moved the
对象 这意味着如果您曾经将
object like off its base or whatever
物体像是脱离了它的底座或别的什么
like that it'll then like clear its
就像这样 它就会像是清除了它的
position so it's actually not the one
所以它实际上不是那个
you want most of the time so it's keep
你想要大部分的时间 所以它是保留的
transform now that I've done that if
现在我已经做到了 如果
you've done it in the correct order you
你按正确的顺序做了这件事
should be able to select the base and
应该能够选择底座和
then move it and the icing should go
然后移动它 糖衣就应该去掉了
with it if it doesn't it means it's
如果它不是 就意味着它
probably parented the other way so again
很可能又是以另一种方式养育孩子
make sure the the object you want to
确保您想要的对象
follow the other one is selected first
首先选择跟随另一个
and then the parent is selected last
然后最后选择父对象
okay so now I'm going to move that up
好的 现在我要把它往上移
along it Z axis so G and then just a
沿着它的Z轴 所以G 然后只有一个
middle tap and pull it up till it's
点击中间 然后把它拉起来 直到它
resting on my counter haha lovely now
躺在我的柜台上哈哈现在很可爱
don't worry about this looking like
不要担心这看起来像
cartoonishly bad in terms of realism I'm
就现实主义而言 我是卡通般的糟糕
going to show you um a button later on
稍后我会给你展示一个按钮
which is is going to make this look
这会让这个看起来
phenomenally realistic um that's going
现象级的现实主义 嗯 这是
to be in some later Parts uh but for now
在后面的部分 呃 但现在
this is fine just whilst we work and uh
在我们工作的时候这样很好 嗯
piece the scene together so for our
把场景拼凑在一起 以便我们
countertop here we need to give it a new
台面在这里 我们需要给它一个新的
material and then underneath the base
材料 然后在底座下面
color you can select not just a color by
您可以选择的颜色不仅仅是一种颜色
clicking the the color but the Little
单击颜色但不是小颜色
Dot next to it that little yellow thing
旁边那个黄色的小东西
doesn't look like a button it is if you
看起来不像按钮 它是 如果你
click that you get this uh this pop up
点击 你会看到这个呃这个弹出窗口
or pop down in this point uh which uh
或者在这一点上往下弹 呃
just gives you a number of options and
只是给了你一系列的选择
the one that we're looking for is image
我们要找的是图像
texture so essentially it's replacing
质感 所以从本质上讲 它正在取代
that input from a flat color to an image
从平面颜色到图像的输入
texture property and it's now black and
纹理属性 现在它是黑色和
it's asking you what image texture so we
它在问你图像的纹理是什么 所以我们
need an image texture now we could go to
需要图像纹理 现在我们可以转到
uh just Google images and just find any
呃 只要谷歌图片 只要找到任何
old marble texture download that uh the
旧大理石纹理下载那个呃
problem usually with uh textures on the
问题通常与呃纹理上的
web is that what most people call A
Web就是大多数人所说的A
texture is not ideal for 3D most
纹理对于大多数3D来说都不是理想的
textures are good for websites but for
纹理对网站有好处 但对
3D we need extra information to tell the
3D我们需要额外的信息来告诉
3D software how the material property
3D软件的材质属性如何
looks like how does it reflect light uh
看起来它是如何反射光线的呢
what are the bumps look like across the
这些凹凸不平的东西是什么样的
surface and all that information is
所有这些信息都是
never available on these sites so to
从未在这些网站上提供过 因此
find those texts you have to go to a
找到那些你必须去的短信
separate dedicated website and the
独立的专用网站和
website that I recommend is polygon and
我推荐的网站是Polygon和
the reason I recommend it is because
我推荐它的原因是
it's mine it's my website it's why I
这是我的这是我的网站这就是为什么我
recommend
推荐
it uh no I started eight years ago
嗯 不 我八年前开始的
because I was uh pretty dissatisfied
因为我呃非常不满意
with the quality of the texture websites
与质感网站的质量
that were available at the time so I
当时是可用的 所以我
used my YouTube money to invest in a
用我的YouTube钱投资了一个
team and some high-tech equipment we
团队和一些高科技设备 我们
went out into the world and we scan
走进这个世界 我们扫描
stuff to a very high quality standard
以非常高的质量标准生产
and over the years we've grown it to
多年来 我们已经成长为
include uh models and hdris as well and
包括呃模型和HDRI 以及
obviously a lot of this stuff is paid um
显然 这些东西中的很多都是付给嗯
but we also have a free range and
但我们也有自由放养的地方
obviously we're going to be using a free
显然 我们将使用免费的
Texture for this part so this is the
这部分的纹理 所以这是
free Texture this is the one we're going
自由质感这就是我们要做的
to use use and first of all although it
使用用法 首先 虽然它
is free you need to sign up for an
是免费的 您需要注册一个
account so you can just sign up with
帐户 这样您就可以注册
Google that's usually the easiest one
谷歌 这通常是最简单的
it's a couple of onboarding questions uh
这是几个入职问题
I would like to actually know how you uh
我真的想知道你是怎么
you know are you a professional are you
你知道吗 你是专业人士吗？
a student that's kind of interesting to
一个对我来说很有趣的学生
me to know that and then when you get to
我知道这一点 然后当你到了
here just going to say continue with
在这里 我只想说继续
free account but pal through that um and
免费帐户 但可以通过UM和
if you click the link in the description
如果您单击描述中的链接
again this is the marble and we just
同样 这是大理石 我们只是
want to hit download and you'll see in
想要点击下载 你就会看到
the bottom right hand corner it's
右下角是
downloading it is a large size but this
下载它是很大的尺寸 但这
because it's 8 K and we've got maps that
因为它是8K 我们有地图
like 16bit depth um to get all of that
就像16位深度Um 才能得到所有这些
accurate information there but once it
准确的信息 但一旦它
is finished it'll just appear in your
完成后 它就会出现在您的
downloads then you just unzip the zip
下载 然后您只需解压缩压缩文件
file as you would normally and then
像往常一样提交文件 然后
finally you should see some glorious
最后你应该看到一些光荣的
high resolution images and ones with
高分辨率图像和具有
extra information like roughness very
额外的信息 比如非常粗糙
very subtle but we'll come through when
非常微妙 但我们会度过难关的
we do the rendom so back into blender
我们做Rendom 所以回到搅拌机
where we've got that image texture we're
在那里我们有图像纹理 我们正在
going to click on open then navigate to
要单击打开 然后导航到
where you unzipped it and then just
在那里你解开它 然后就
click on the one that's ends uh with C
点击以C结尾的那个
in the name and then just hit open and
在名字里 然后点击打开和
here it is okay and it looks great up
在这里 它可以 它看起来很棒
close only problem is of course look at
关闭唯一的问题当然是看
that reflection so Bland so fake and as
那倒影让布兰德如此虚伪
I mentioned before fake is the enemy and
我之前提到过 假是敌人
you need to uh squash it by just adding
你需要 呃 通过添加
variant so that's where our roughness
所以这就是我们粗暴的地方
map is going to come in and while we
地图就要进来了 而我们
could try to add it in here this section
我可以试着把它添加到这一部分
on the right hand side it's actually not
在右手边 实际上不是
where you do most of your material work
你的大部分材料工作都是在这里完成的
because this is kind of like a
因为这有点像是
simplified dumb down version it doesn't
简化的简化版本 它不是
really it's it gets a little bit
真的 它变得有点
complicated when you try and add too
当您尝试添加时也会很复杂
many things to it cuz there's like too
它有很多东西 因为那里也有
many menus and drop downs and all that
许多菜单和下拉菜单以及所有这些
kind of stuff so instead if you go to
类似的东西 如果你去
your shading tab at the top of the
选项卡顶部的着色选项卡
screen there this will change the layout
屏幕在那里 这将更改布局
of the screen to something completely
完全变成了屏幕上的东西
different we haven't seen before and
我们以前从未见过的不同之处
lots of Windows actually too many I
很多Windows实际上太多我
never actually need this one on the
从没有真正需要过这一次
right hand side so where you just Mouse
右手边 所以你只需用鼠标
over where you've got the divider and
关于你在哪里有分隔器和
then just right click and then say join
然后只需右键单击 然后说加入
areas and then you want want to join it
区域 然后你想加入它
to the left to close it and then I'll do
在左边合上它 然后我会做
the same here cuz I've never needed
在这里也是一样 因为我从来不需要
those on the left hand side so I've just
那些在左手边 所以我只是
got my view at the top here and then
在这里看到了我的顶端 然后
this one here and the Reason by the way
这是这里的 顺便说一句原因
this looks different um than what we had
这个看起来和我们以前的不一样
before is because this is the material
之前是因为这是材料
preview but you can change it back to
预览 但您可以将其更改回
what we had before by clicking that so
我们之前所拥有的 通过点击它
material preview by the way it's the
材料预览顺便说一句 这是
same it's it's a rendered mode but it's
同样 它是渲染模式 但它
using uh lights a Different Light setup
使用呃灯光设置不同的灯光
basically just an hdri which is like a
基本上只是一个HDRI 就像一个
fake kind of light and reflection map
假的灯光和反射贴图种类
just so that you can quickly preview
这样你就可以快速预览
materials and really you could use
材料 而且你真的可以用
either or um they both kind of show the
或者 嗯 他们都表现出了
material but yeah let's use this one
材料 但好的 我们用这个吧
okay but the bit that we're looking for
好的 但我们要找的是
is here so this section here is your
在这里 所以这一部分是您的
node setup and it's actually an exact
节点设置 它实际上是一个精确的
duplicate of what we did over here
复制我们在这里做过的事情
because this on the right hand side is
因为右手边的这个是
the simplified version if you're just
简化版 如果你只是
doing like a quick change you might want
做一个你可能想要的快速改变
to use this but over here this is what's
使用这个 但在这里 这就是
actually happening to it underneath the
实际上发生在它的下面
hood right so you can see as I change
引擎盖是对的 所以你可以看到我改变的样子
this on the right hand inside that is
里面右手边的这个就是
also changing there so they are linked
也在那里更改 以便将它们链接在一起
so the way nodes work is basically a
因此 节点的工作方式基本上是
left to right function so we start over
从左到右的功能 因此我们重新开始
here with our image texture it goes into
在这里 我们的图像纹理将进入
our Shader which is the material for uh
我们的着色器 它是呃
this plane and then it comes out into a
这架飞机 然后它出来变成一个
material output and that's what is fed
材料输出 这就是提供的
into the final uh Shader so essentially
进入最终的 呃 着色器 所以基本上
we could put we could do anything like
我们可以说我们可以做任何事情 比如
for example and this is one of the value
例如 这是其中一个值
of nodes is between these two nodes we
在这两个节点之间 我们
could add another node like for example
可以添加另一个节点 例如
I could hit shift a to add again same
我可以按下Shift a来再次添加相同的内容
hoty works everywhere and then I could
霍蒂在任何地方工作 然后我就可以
add in like a hue saturation value node
像色调饱和值节点一样添加
and then I could change the Hue of my
然后我可以改变我的
marble to look blue right or or
大理石看起来是蓝色的右边还是或者
something else um so that's the power of
其他的东西 嗯 所以这就是
nose and you could just keep going
鼻子和你可以继续前进
adding in adjustments and everything you
加上调整和你所做的一切
want um so nodes very very flexible um
想要这个所以节点非常非常灵活的这个
they do look daunting because they get
他们看起来确实令人望而生畏 因为他们
all these like you know squid looking
所有这些就像你知道的乌贼一样
lines going everywhere um but it's very
队伍到处都是 嗯 但它非常
very convenient very customizable okay
非常方便 非常可定制 好的
but we want to add something to our
但我们想给我们的
roughness so so that we don't have a
粗糙 所以我们不会有一个
flat uh single value roughness which is
平坦的呃单值粗糙度 这是
what that is currently we want to use
这就是我们目前想使用的
that map that we just downloaded so uh
我们刚刚下载的地图 所以呢
one you could hit shift a and then add
您可以按下Shift a键 然后添加
an image text this way but actually we
这样的图文 但实际上我们
could also just drag out from that input
也可以从该输入拖出
there and then just do a release and
就在那里 然后做一次释放
it'll now say what do you want to add in
它现在会说您要添加什么内容
this input and we could type in image
这个输入 我们可以输入图像
texture color and then hit uh enter Then
纹理颜色 然后按呃Enter 然后
here go to that same place that we
在这里 我们去同一个地方 我们
unzipped it and then we're looking for
把它解开然后我们要找的是
the one with roughness in the name so
名字中带有粗糙度的那个
Ness in the name and then hit open okay
Ness的名字 然后点击打开 好的
so this is better right you can kind of
所以这样更好 对吧 你可以
see we've got some detail there but it
看 我们有一些细节 但它
doesn't look quite right something is
看起来不太对劲有些事
not going right um it's because when you
不是很顺利 因为当你
add an image texture um blunder doesn't
添加图像纹理UM错误不会
really know what type of information it
真正知道它是什么类型的信息
is yet and by default it's looking at
在默认情况下 它正在查看
the color information is though there
颜色信息就在那里
even though there isn't really color
即使没有真正的颜色
there so instead we need to tell blender
所以我们需要告诉搅拌机
this is a special map and we're just
这是一张特别的地图 我们只是
looking at the values right so
正确地看待这些价值
essentially the color space here we need
从本质上讲 我们需要的颜色空间
to change it from srgb where it's a
要将其从sRGB更改为
standard photo color to instead
标准照片颜色改为
non-color data or just non- color I
非彩色数据或仅非彩色数据
guess they've changed it um but now you
我猜他们已经改了 但是现在你
can see that looks correct right so look
我可以看到它看起来是正确的 所以请看
at all that we got scratches we got
不管怎么说 我们都被抓伤了
smudges it's infinitely more realistic
弄脏了它更逼真得多
uh than what we had
呃比我们拥有的要多
previously so beyond that though we
在此之前 尽管我们
could also add in little tiny bumps okay
也可以添加一些微小的凹凸 好吗？
so bumps are in a place you would not
所以隆起的地方是你不会想到的
expect there's not a bump value here
希望这里没有凹凸值
it's actually under normal so normal you
实际上是低于正常的 所以你很正常
hear that word a lot in 3D it just
在3D中经常听到这个词 它只是
basically means the face which direction
基本上是指哪个方向的脸
is the face pointing right so if this is
脸部是否指向右侧 所以如果这是
your face of the plane you're pointing
你所指的飞机的脸
this way that's the normal right but you
这样做是正常的 但是你
can change the normal information to
可以将正常信息更改为
kind of tweak it to pretend like there
有点微调 假装就是这样
is detail in that okay essentially we
细节是好的 基本上我们
can plug in a specialized map called a
可以插入一种称为
normal map okay so we're going to drag
法线贴图好的 所以我们要拖动
out from that normal map and then relas
从该法线贴图中移出 然后重新绘制
release and then image texture that's
然后释放图像纹理 这是
the last used thing that's the one we
最后一件用过的东西是我们
want I'm just going to click color then
想要吗？我只需要点击颜色
drop and then hit open go to that same
拖放 然后点击打开 转到相同的
folder and then this is the one the
文件夹 然后这就是
purple one it's the weirdest looking map
紫色的 这是看起来最奇怪的地图
you always know you're looking at a uh a
你总是知道你面对的是一个呃
CG texture map directory cuz it's the
CG纹理贴图目录 因为它是
purple one and it's got nrm in the name
紫色的 它的名字里有NRM
for normal and hit open and just like
正常情况下 点击打开 就像
before it's not going to be correct
在它变得不正确之前
because it it thinks this is a color
因为它认为这是一种颜色
image texture just like for photos so we
图像纹理就像照片一样 所以我们
need to change it again to non-color
需要再次将其更改为非彩色
data and now you would think that would
数据 现在你会认为这会
fix it but no it looks even worse what
修好它 但不 它看起来更糟什么
did we do the problem is is we need to
我们这样做了吗？问题是我们需要
convert this image texture into
将此图像纹理转换为
something this can read so we need to
一些这个能读的东西 所以我们需要
put another node in between here so the
在这里的中间放置另一个节点 这样
node is found under shift a a for add
在用于添加的Shift a a下找到节点
then Vector normal map so click and then
然后单击向量法线贴图 然后
just drop it here so it highlights
把它放在这里 这样它就会突出显示
between it and then just drop it and it
在它之间 然后把它和它放在一起
will now finally be correct and if I go
现在终于是正确的了 如果我去
full screen with control space I didn't
带有控制空间的全屏显示 我没有
mention that before but yeah control
之前提到过 但控制住了
space and then you can uh Go full screen
空格键 然后你可以 嗯 全屏显示
and you can see we've got very subtle
你可以看到我们已经变得非常微妙
little little chips and divots across
小小的筹码和草皮
the texture along with those smudges and
质地以及那些污点和
uh it just looks way more believable
呃 只是看起来更可信
means you don't have to worry about this
意味着你不必担心这件事
part of your scene it's just going to
你的场景的一部分 它只会
work and you're going to get all that
工作 你就会得到这一切
detail for free and um just makes life a
免费的细节 嗯 只是让生活变得
little bit easier but it is a lot of
稍微简单一点 但它有很多
work like what you've just made is a PBR
就像你刚刚做的是PBR一样工作
Shader and yeah it's it's a lot of work
着色器 是的 这是一项繁重的工作
all those little maps and everything and
所有那些小地图和所有的东西
having to know which setting is which um
必须知道哪种设置是哪种
but it is a very common thing to learn
但这是一件很常见的事情
so that's why I wanted to include it in
这就是为什么我想把它包括在
here um if I could plug my own website
在这里 嗯 如果我能把我自己的网站
again though I will say we did hear you
不过 我要再说一次 我们确实听到了
cuz a lot of people say that so we
因为很多人都这么说所以我们
actually made an add-on called the
实际上制作了一个名为
polygon add-on which I'll actually show
我将实际展示的Polygon附加组件
you how to install later on cuz that is
你以后怎么安装 因为那就是
actually important for 3D cuz you use a
实际上对3D很重要 因为您使用了
lot of add-ons but to plug it very
有很多附加组件 但要把它插上
quickly it actually does all of that
很快 它就能真正做到这一切
without you having to leave blender so
不用你离开搅拌机
it'll download the texture for you there
它将在那里为您下载纹理
we go see it's uh downloading it's
我们去看它 呃 正在下载它
actually faster through the add-on and
实际上更快地通过附加组件和
then once you've got it you just hit
然后 一旦你得到它 你就会击中
apply and then it will do all of that
申请 然后它将完成所有这些
node work for you in the background and
节点在后台为您工作
it'll just apply it to the mesh for you
它只需将其应用于网格即可
um so you don't have to do all that all
嗯 这样你就不用做所有这些了
the time and in fact most people I think
当时 事实上 我认为大多数人
if you're working on Big scenes you're
如果你在拍大场面 你就是
using libraries uh you're using add-ons
使用库 呃 你在使用附加组件
like this so you don't have to do it all
像这样 这样你就不用做所有的事了
manually all the time but it is
所有时间都是手动的 但它是
important to know the process so that's
重要的是要了解这个过程 这样才能
why I wanted to show it but anyways this
为什么我想展示它 但不管怎样 这
was our material and we are happy with
是我们的材料 我们很高兴
it well done let's go back to the layout
It做得好让我们回到布局上来
tab and now we're going to do one more
现在我们要再做一次
thing so you see our dut base here let's
所以你可以看到我们这里的DUT基座
just isolate this doughnut for one
把这个甜甜圈单独拿出来
moment here by hitting forward slash
在这里通过击打前斜杠
which I mentioned previously okay when
我之前提到过 当
you're in forward this is isolate mode
你在前进 这是隔离模式
which means it's literally turning off
这意味着它真的要关闭了
everything including the lamp which is
所有的东西 包括那盏灯
why it's dark but if you turn on
为什么天黑了 但如果你打开
material preview then you get this so
材料预览 然后你就会看到这个
this is okay uh but if you look look at
这没问题 呃 但是如果你看一下
real references of donuts you'll see
你会看到甜甜圈的真实参考
that it's typically whiter around the
它通常是更白的周围
middle and the reason for that is as I
中间的原因是因为我
mentioned before the way it Cooks right
之前提到的烹饪方式是正确的
it's only like half submerged and then
它只有一半被淹没 然后
it's flipped and it means that the bits
它被翻转了 这意味着这些比特
that are closest to the surface are
离地表最近的是
cooked less so there's usually like a
烹调较少 所以通常会有一种
whiter part around the rim and I mean
边缘周围的白色部分 我是说
really this is just an excuse to show
真的 这只是一个展示自己的借口
you another part of blender which is
你是搅拌机的另一个部分
texture paint so at the top there click
纹理绘制 因此在顶部单击
the texture paint tab and again let's go
纹理绘制选项卡 然后再一次开始
into isolate mode with our donut there
带着我们的甜甜圈进入隔离模式
um why are we not seeing okay there we
嗯 为什么我们看不到好的我们
go so what texture paint uh does it lets
去吧 呃 它让什么质感的油漆
you paint directly onto your mesh but if
您可以直接在网格上进行绘制 但如果
we try doing it you can see nothing's
我们试着去做 你什么都看不到
happening and it does give you a warning
如果发生了 它确实给了你一个警告
at the body missing textures detected so
在身体上检测到缺失的纹理
to paint you're painting into an image
为了画出你正在画成的图像
and the image doesn't exist yet so we
图像还不存在 所以我们
have to give it one so go to the
必须给它一个 所以去
material Tab and then here where we got
材料选项卡 然后是我们获得的位置
base color we set it up as yellow but
基色我们将其设置为黄色 但
we're actually just going to override it
我们实际上只是要推翻它
now so click that little yellow dot
现在点击那个小黄点
again and then say image texture so now
一遍又一遍地说图像纹理现在就是这样
it's black doesn't have an image so and
它是黑色的 没有图像 所以
instead of clicking open we're going to
我们将不再单击打开 而是
click new so we're going to be creating
单击新建 以便我们将创建
a brand new image and let's call this
一种全新的形象 让我们称之为
donut base we could make this higher res
甜甜圈底座我们可以把这个做得更高
if we want but don't this is more than
如果我们想要 但不是 这不仅仅是
enough for a donut base that's fine and
足够做一个甜甜圈底座了 这很好
uh this will just save us time to color
呃 这只会节省我们涂颜色的时间
this will just fill the uh it'll fill
这只会填满呃它会填满的
the the the image for us with a flat
给我们的形象是一个扁平的
color so going to go for something
所以我要买点颜色的东西
pretty similar to what we had before a
与我们之前的情况非常相似
nice yellowy color like that and by the
很漂亮的黄色 就像这样
way make sure you're all the way bright
一定要确保你一直都很聪明
otherwise your donut is uh is going to
否则你的甜甜圈就会呃
be a little bit dark so yeah there we go
有点黑暗 所以耶 我们走吧
all right and then hit okay and once
好的 然后打好 然后再打一次
we've done that you should I mean it
我们已经做过了 你应该 我是认真的
should be over there on the Le hand side
应该在那边的Le Hand一侧
but if it doesn't pop up you can just
但如果它没有弹出来 你可以
select it from the drop down donut base
从下拉列表中选择甜甜圈底座
and there we go so now we're in this
我们就这样走了 所以现在我们在这里
state look what I can do ooh fancy so I
看我能做什么 哦 幻想 所以我
don't know why I said it like that um
不知道我为什么这么说 嗯
but we can paint directly onto our mesh
但我们可以直接在我们的网格上绘画
so to understand this because it's kind
所以理解这一点是因为它很友善
of weird you can also paint directly
奇怪的是 你也可以直接作画
over here and you might be thinking like
在这里 你可能会想
well how does it know like how do I know
它怎么知道 我怎么知道
which part over here is actually going
这里的哪个部分实际上正在进行
to be painted over onto the donut there
被涂在那里的甜甜圈上
you might not care but it's uh it's
你可能不在乎 但是 呃 这是
actually good to understand how it works
其实很高兴了解它是如何工作的
so basically this mesh here it has to be
所以基本上这里的网状物必须是
unwrapped over onto this left hand side
展开到左手边
here cuz that's the only way to uh have
在这里 因为这是唯一的办法 呃
a 2d texture 2D flat image be applied to
将2D纹理2D平面图像应用于
a mesh is to unwrap it in some way I
网格是以某种方式展开它的 即
mean there's projection I'm not getting
意思是有我看不到的投影
into that uh to unwrap it and unwrapping
放进那个 呃 拆开 拆开
is essentially like there is a meme
从本质上讲就像是存在一种迷因
actually that that explains it um but if
实际上 这就解释了 嗯 但是如果
you have like a chocolate right that is
你有像巧克力一样的权利 那是
wrapped in some tin foil if you flatten
用锡纸包裹着 如果你压平的话
it out that is essentially UV unwrapping
结果表明 这本质上是紫外线解包
there are are little places in that
那里面只有很小的地方
wrapping where there had to be a cut
包扎必须有割伤的地方
right and then that cut was wrapped
好的 然后那个伤口被包起来了
around the object that's what uvon
围绕着物体 这就是我们所要做的
wrapping is so the reason this works for
包装就是这样起作用的原因
us is because the cuts are actually
我们是因为削减实际上是
already in in place for default objects
已为默认对象准备好
so this Taurus is already perfectly UV
所以这颗金牛座已经完全是紫外线了
unwrapped so we don't have to do
打开包装 这样我们就不需要
anything I did want to mention it though
不过 我想提的任何事
because it's important to understand UV
因为了解紫外线很重要
unwrapping anyways so we could actually
无论如何都要打开 这样我们就可以真正
paint directly on here as I mentioned
就像我提到的那样 直接在这里作画
white is a little bit too extreme though
不过 白色有点太极端了
so I'm going to click that and choose a
所以我要点击它并选择一个
color first of all I'm going to select
首先我要选颜色
the eye dropper and then not click over
滴管 然后不点击
here cuz that's got shading information
这是因为这里有阴影信息
I'm going to click on the left hand side
我要点击左侧
so we get the exact color and then I'm
所以我们得到了确切的颜色 然后我
going to make it closer to White so not
会让它更接近怀特 所以不会
fully white cuz that'll be too far but
全白的 因为那太远了 但是
closer to White and I'm also going to
更接近怀特 我也要
change the strength of my
改变我的力量
brush uh yeah I'll make about halfway
刷子 呃 好的 我会做一半的
and then now I can do paints across it
然后现在我可以在它上面画画了
and this will enable you to get a much
这将使您能够获得更多
more natural feel um because you'll have
更自然的感觉 嗯 因为你会有
just like in fact I might even go a
就像事实上我甚至可能会去
little bit softer and that way you can
稍微柔和一点 这样你就可以
kind of just paint across it and this is
就像是在上面画画 这是
very forgiving because we've got icing
非常宽容 因为我们有糖衣
that's going to go over the top of it um
这将超过它的顶部 嗯
but that's good we don't want it to be
但这很好 我们不想让它成为
too too extreme let's just make it I
太极端了 我们就这么做吧
might go the other way make this a
可能会走另一条路让这成为一个
little bit more saturated anyways that's
更饱和一点 不管怎么说 这是
basically all we need to do we just want
基本上我们需要做的就是
to just dab our toes into the field of
只是把我们的脚趾轻拍在…的领域
uh texture painting I would say texture
呃 质感绘画 我会说质感
painting by the way it's one of the
顺便说一句 它是世界上
weaker areas of blender it's actually
搅拌机较弱的区域实际上是
due for an update at some point in the
中的某个时间点进行更新
future um but it doesn't do like you
未来 嗯 但它不像你
can't paint into like the uh the height
不能画成这样 呃 高度
information or the roughness information
信息或粗糙度信息
at the same time like you can with
同时 就像您可以使用
substance painter but
物质画家 但是
it's it's got basic functionality
它有基本的功能
now importantly this is an image but
现在 重要的是 这是一个图像 但是
it's not saved into your blend file it
它不会保存到您的混合文件中
still needs to be manually saved so see
仍然需要手动保存 因此请参见
at the top leftand corner there it's got
在左上角 它有
image with a star if you see that star
如果你看到一颗星星 你就会看到那颗星星
it means you've got changes that haven't
这意味着您有一些尚未更改的内容
been saved so we need to go image and
已被保存 所以我们需要进行图像处理
then save and specify where are we going
然后保存并指定我们要去的地方
to put our image because if we don't do
把我们的形象放在一边因为如果我们不这样做
this uh we're going to lose it so it has
这个 呃 我们会失去它 所以它有
to be saved somewhere so I'm just going
在某个地方被拯救 所以我要去
to save it
为了拯救它
yeah anywhere it has to be saved
是啊 在任何需要保存的地方
somewhere because it will not be saved
因为它不会被保存在某个地方
as part of the blend fob very important
作为混合离岸价的一部分 非常重要
to know that otherwise you can lose
要知道 否则你可能会输
texture paint work that you've done but
纹理绘制工作 但您已经完成了
there we go so now to bring back
我们现在要带回来了
everything remember if it looks like
一切都要记住 如果它看起来像
where's the rest of my seene gone see
我剩下的时间都去哪里了
the top left hand corner local means
左上角表示本地
it's isolated mode so that means you
这是隔离模式 所以这意味着你
just have to hit forward slash again and
只需再打一次前斜杠
it brings back everything and there we
它把一切都带回来了 我们在那里
are so that's the extent of uh this part
所以这就是呃这部分的范围
of the tutorial as I mentioned the uh
就像我提到的 呃
some of you might be wondering when are
你们中的一些人可能会想知道什么时候
we going to make that lovely uh
我们要把那个可爱的呃
subsurface scattering we're going to do
我们要做的是地下散射
that in the future after we do the
在我们做完这件事之后
sprinkles cuz it's too hard to see at
洒水是因为太难看清了
this point so there we go guys join me
这一点 我们走吧 伙计们 加入我
in the next part and I'll see you there
在下一部分 我们在那里见